Torn apart by betrayal. Separated by war. Bound by love.
Atonement is a drama, romance film directed by Joe Wright.
A young girl irrevocably changes the course of several lives when she
accuses her older sister's lover of a crime he did not commit.
Robbie Turner, played by James McAvoy.
Cecilia Tallis, played by Keira Knightley.
Briony Tallis (Age 13), played by Saoirse Ronan.
Briony Tallis (Age 18), played by Romola Garai.
Briony Tallis (Age 77), played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Grace Turner, played by Brenda Blethyn.
Atonement is a 2007 romantic war tragedy film directed by Joe Wright and starring James
McAvoy, Keira Knightley, Saoirse Ronan, Romola Garai, and Vanessa Redgrave.
It is based on the 2001 novel by Ian McEwan.
The film chronicles a crime and its consequences over
six decades, beginning in the 1930s.
It was produced for StudioCanal and filmed in England.
Distributed in most of the world by Universal Studios, it was released theatrically in the United Kingdom
on 7 September 2007 and in North America exactly three months later on 7 December 2007.
Atonement opened both the 2007 Vancouver International Film
Festival and the 64th Venice International Film Festival.
Wright, at age 35, was the youngest director ever to open the Venice event.
The film was a commercial success and earned a worldwide gross of
approximately $129 million against a budget of $30 million.
Critics praised its acting, emotional depth, Wright's direction, Dario Marianelli's score, the
cinematography, editing, visuals, and the film's incorporation of historic events.
Among numerous accolades, Atonement was nominated in seven categories at the 80th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, Best Supporting Actress (for Ronan), Best Adapted Screenplay, and Best Original Score, which it won.
It also garnered fourteen nominations at the 61st British Academy Film Awards, winning both Best Film
and Production Design; and won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Drama.
The film explores themes of new love, sibling
relationship, based on novel or book, wind, nurse.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.